Now, the knowledge of this is the knowledge of the roots.
Şimdi, bunun bilgisi köklerin bilgisidir.
Whatever we have achieved is the knowledge of the tree.
Başardığımız her ne varsa o, ağacın bilgisidir.
But if the tree outgrows itself from its root, then it may die.
Ancak ağaç köklerinden aşırı büyüp kendini aşarsa, o zaman ölebilir.
So it is time that we should find out about the roots.
Bu yüzden artık kökleri keşfetmemizin zamanı geldi.
And to know about that, we have to become a subtler being.
Ve bunu bilmek için daha süptil bir varlık haline gelmeliyiz.
At this human awareness, you cannot understand.
Bunu insan bilinciyle anlayamazsınız.
But sometimes it challenges the ego of people.
Ama bazen bu, insanların egosunu zorlar.
They think, "Why not?
“Neden olmasın?” diye düşünürler.
I am such and such, why shouldn’t I know?" But you cannot.
“Ben şuyum, buyum, neden bilmeyeyim?” Ama bilemezsiniz.
As you have to have a microscope to see things
Nesneleri derinlemesine görmek için mikroskoba ihtiyacınızın olması gibi
deeply, in the same way you have to have this new awareness within you, this dynamic awareness.
aynı şekilde, içinizde bu yeni farkındalığa, bu dinamik farkındalığa sahip olmanız gerekir.
Of course, the nature of Self is that it is collectively conscious,
Elbette, Benliğin doğası kolektif bilinçli olmasıdır,
that it is the source of peace and bliss, that it is the truth and love.
huzur ve mutluluğun kaynağı olmasıdır, gerçek ve sevgi olmasıdır.
That’s the nature.
Doğası budur.
And you become that.
Ve siz de o olursunuz. O, olursunuz.
It’s not only mental, but you really become.
Bu sadece zihinsel bir şey değil, gerçekten o olursunuz.
Because whatever is mental is artificial
Çünkü zihinsel olan her şey yapaydır